<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>quant on Jirong&#39;s sandbox</title>
    <link>/categories/quant/</link>
    <description>Recent content in quant on Jirong&#39;s sandbox</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 11:50:49 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/categories/quant/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Plans for trend following strategy in futures using continuous forecast</title>
      <link>/post/plans-for-trend-following-strategy-in-futures-using-binary-forecast/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 11:50:49 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/plans-for-trend-following-strategy-in-futures-using-binary-forecast/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;trend-following-strategy-in-futures-using-non-binary-forecasts&#34;&gt;Trend following strategy in futures using non binary forecasts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;project-motivation&#34;&gt;Project motivation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As David Ricardo, a British economist in the 19th century once said, ‘cut short your losses and let your profits trend’ allude to the point that trend following as a profitable strategy could exist even back then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having read AQR’s papers on the Time Series Momentum (TSMOM, I am keen to explore this topic in the futures space (Moskowitz, T. J., Ooi, Y. H., &amp;amp; Pedersen, L. H. (2012)). This strategy has been explored by the Quantopian community and the source code &amp;amp; dataset could be found in this github repository (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/quantopian/research_public/tree/master/advanced_sample_analyses/TSMOM&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://github.com/quantopian/research_public/tree/master/advanced_sample_analyses/TSMOM&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides AQR papers, I have also followed closely the work of Robert Carver, an ex-MAN AHL quant who specialized in the space of intermediate to long term trend-following futures strategies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;dataset&#34;&gt;Dataset&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Futures dataset across 4 asset classes: Indices, Bonds, Currencies, Commodites&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quantopian datset up till 2016
Presumably stiched through backward, forward, proportional adjusted methodology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CHRIS Wiki Continuous Futures dataset in Quandl (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.quandl.com/data/CHRIS-Wiki-Continuous-Futures&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://www.quandl.com/data/CHRIS-Wiki-Continuous-Futures&lt;/a&gt;)
Datasets are stitched with continuous raw non-adjusted prices but not backward, forward, proportional adjusted. There are varaitions of front contract, second contract, third contract, etc.
To use it for data modelling purposes, I would have to assume that rollover is required on certain date (through volume or open interest)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Steven Analytics Futures dataset in Quandl (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.quandl.com/databases/SCF/data&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://www.quandl.com/databases/SCF/data&lt;/a&gt;)
Stiched datasets with variations of backward, forward, proportional adjustment
Behind paywall&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;data-mining&#34;&gt;Data mining&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In AQR papers, the authors experimented with fixed lookback periods of 1 year and deciding on the trading signal for the next month i.e. if price of an asset increase over 1 year period, the trading signal for next month would be long. Reverse holds when price of an asset decreased. Position of each asset is based on lookback exponential standard deviation of daily returns with annualized volatility of 40%. Agglomerated to a portfolio, the annualized standard deviation is closer to 12% with approximate sharpe of 1.0 over 30 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I intend to carry out in this research paper instead is something closer to Robert Carver’s methdology,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First, compute 3 types of continuous forecasts based on the following,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Exponential moving averages (e.g. 8-32, 16-64, 32-138)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Raw forecast: Take the difference between pair of moving averages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Divide raw forecast by instrument-risk (volatility of instrument in price unit) to get a risk adjusted forecast.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Breakouts&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Raw Forecast, scaled price in range: (Pt – Ravg/med N) / (RmaxN – RminN)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Divide raw forecast by instrument-risk (volatility of instrument in price unit) to get a risk adjusted forecast.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Carry strategy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Raw Forecast = (Front contract price – Next contract price)/ distance between contract&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Divide raw forecast by instrument-risk (volatility of instrument in price unit) to get a risk adjusted forecast.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rescale the signals in point 1 to obtain average absolute signal strength of 10 for each individual forecasts across time. Rescaling factor based on expanding window of median acoss all instruments.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Combine signals in point 2 across systems. Bootstrapping or block bootstrapping with expanding window is used to find the optimal weights (on in-sample or out-of sample data. Requires guidance on this). Cap the signal at -20 to +20.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;With diversification, the combined signal in point 3 will bring down the average signal strength to below 10. A forecast diversification multiplier (FDM) is required to bring the signal to average of 10 again. FDM  = 1/[sqrt(W X H X Wtranspose)], where W is the forecast weights, H is the correlation matrix of forecast values in point 1&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Position allocation is based on lookback exponential volatility of 25 trading days. May look into stratification by asset classes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;E.g. 25% volatility target on 1,000,000 portfolio would indicate annualized risk of 250,000 with daily risk of 250,000/16 = 15,625&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If there are 4 assets classes, each asset class is allocated 3,906 of daily risk&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If there are 4 instruments in each asset class. This would be approximately 977 dollars daily risk per instrument. Signal of +10 for an instrument would indicate 977 dollars of risk and +20 (strong positve forecasts) would indicate 1954 dollars of risk.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Entry and exit rules are based on continuous forecasts instead of binary entries and exits. i.e. strategy is dependent on the state of the forecasts&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;evaluation-of-strategies&#34;&gt;Evaluation of strategies&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sharpe/ Sortino ratio&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Calmar ratio/ Max drawdown&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Beta/ Fama-French 3 factor analysis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Skew/ kurtosis of strategies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;potential-challenges-and-require-further-deliberation-on-following-pointers&#34;&gt;Potential challenges and require further deliberation on following pointers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stitching of futures dataset.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When and how do we rollover in practice?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is it essential to avoid front contracts? To avoid the ‘oil contract’ negative prices issue in early 2020?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do we always remain in the contract with highest volume/ open interest?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do we find optimal weights in 3.3 in practice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do we use boostrapping properly to avoid in-sample bias?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In optimisation, do we usually optimize based on in-sample data or do we also consider the results in validation dataset? E.g. Sharpe ratio in in-sample data and validation dataset shouldn’t differ by x%. If so, is this difference filtered by the program. And would this run a risk of curve-fitting?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hurst, Brian, Yao Hua Ooi, and Lasse Heje Pedersen. &amp;ldquo;A century of evidence on trend-following investing.&amp;ldquo; The Journal of Portfolio Management 44, no. 1 (2017): 15-29.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Moskowitz, Tobias J., Yao Hua Ooi, and Lasse Heje Pedersen. &amp;ldquo;Time series momentum.&amp;ldquo; Journal of financial economics 104, no. 2 (2012): 228-250.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Carver, Robert. Systematic Trading: A unique new method for designing trading and investing systems. Harriman House Limited, 2015.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Carver, Robert.Leveraged Trading. Harriman House Limited, 2019.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developing a performance monitoring component in my fully automated algorithmic trading system</title>
      <link>/post/designing-and-deploying-a-fully-automated-algorithmic-trading-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 11:50:49 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/designing-and-deploying-a-fully-automated-algorithmic-trading-system/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;developing-a-performance-monitoring-system-for-my-algorithmic-trading-system&#34;&gt;Developing a performance monitoring system for my algorithmic trading system&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s one thing to backtest your signals and forecasts on historical data but it&amp;rsquo;s a completely different animal in terms of execution. I have written about this &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/datadriveninvestor/designing-and-building-a-fully-automated-algorithmic-trading-portfolio-management-system-6945c6c87620/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another important component of setting up an algorithmic trading system is performance monitoring. Some important questions I had in mind while developing this component,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do I measure my slippage? Commissions paid?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are my daily returns? And how do I measure performance of my strategy while accounting for inflow and outflow of cash into the account?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-do-i-measure-my-slippage&#34;&gt;How do I measure my slippage?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On this front, I use &lt;a href=&#34;https://ib-insync.readthedocs.io/_modules/ib_insync/flexreport.html&#34;&gt;FlexReport&lt;/a&gt;
function (using REST API) from ib_insync to query the trades made on that day. The function will query the XML report from Interactive Brokers which I subsequently format for daily reporting purposes. The queryId specification had to be set up via IB web account management system. Unfortunately this expires annually which means you have to find a way to remind yourself to refresh this queryId manually every year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;## Code for querying from IB
report = FlexReport(token, queryId) 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some trivial code is then written to format the XML into this format below for my email notification,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/post/img/Slippage.png&#34; alt=&#34;/post/img/Slippage.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-are-my-daily-returns-how-do-i-measure-performance-of-my-strategy-while-accounting-for-inflow-and-outflow-of-cash-into-the-account&#34;&gt;What are my daily returns? How do I measure performance of my strategy while accounting for inflow and outflow of cash into the account?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past, I de-prioritised and placed development of performance monitoring at the bottom of my backlog as I could easily query sophiscated performance figures from IB. You may find some of the figures in my blog &lt;a href=&#34;https://jironghuang.github.io/portfolio/portfolio/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Increasingly, however, I found that it is important to understand the performance drivers of portfolio performance by instruments and strategies. To analyze at this granular level, I would have to capture the daily/ hourly levels and returns of instruments and strategies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To do that, the system triggers a request to take an accounting snapshot of the portfolio every hour,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/post/img/snapshot.png&#34; alt=&#34;/post/img/snapshot.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what if there is inflow and outflow of cash - you may ask? I simply rely on Time Weighted Return Formula.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TWR = [(1+HP1) X&amp;hellip;.(1+HPN)] - 1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;where TWR = Time weighted return&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;n = Number of sub-periods&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HP = (End Value of Day- Initial Value of Day + Cash Flow)/ (Initial Value + Cashflow)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HPN = Return for sub period n&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the portfolio level, the inflow and outflow would the net cash inflow into the account. At the instrument level, the inflow and outflow would be the net buy/sell trades on that day. You would also have to adjust the instrument asset value to &amp;lsquo;the equity value&amp;rsquo; by downsizing through the overall portfolio leverage factor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may find the implementation of measuring time weighted returns at overall portfolio level in the appendix.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After all that is mentioned and done, what could I do? I could plot some fancy equity curves as shown below,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/post/img/strategy1_equity_curve.png&#34; alt=&#34;/post/img/strategy1_equity_curve.png&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/post/img/strategy2_equity_curve.png&#34; alt=&#34;/post/img/strategy2_equity_curve.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could also measure realized rolling volatility and do crazy stuff (but unimportant in my opinion) like fama-french 3, 5, or gazillion factors analysis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-in-my-backlog-for-further-enhancement-of-performance-monitoring&#34;&gt;What is in my backlog for further enhancement of performance monitoring?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understanding performance drivers systematically with data captured i.e. break down overall portfolio returns into weighted performance drivers by strategies, instruments and time-frame.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pushing data files into a relational or non-relational database. But as much as possible, I will try to limit interaction between the trading system and databases during trading hours. In the past, I observed concurrency issues while using SQLite and database server &amp;lsquo;hanging&amp;rsquo; while using relational database such as Mysql. Another alternative would be to host the servers in the cloud. But that would mean I have to pay for extra costs and worry about connectivity issues. Sometimes plain old files could just work?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Impact of exchange rate effect on portfolio performance. I wrote and created a repository on this in the past. You may visit the link &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jironghuang/RemoveExchangeRateEffects&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;appendix&#34;&gt;Appendix&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/post/img/accounting.png&#34; alt=&#34;/post/img/accounting.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Designing, Building and Deploying a Fully Automated Algorithmic Trading System</title>
      <link>/post/developing-an-accounting-and-performance-monitoring-system-for-my-algorithmic-trading-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 11:50:49 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/developing-an-accounting-and-performance-monitoring-system-for-my-algorithmic-trading-system/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;designing-building-and-deploying-a-fully-automated-algorithmic-trading-system&#34;&gt;Designing, Building and Deploying a Fully Automated Algorithmic Trading System&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I developed several inter-day trading/ portfolio management algorithms, I also embarked on a journey in parallel to develop a fully automated execution framework that could satisfy my requirements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Previously orders were executed manually after signals are generated automatically.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;requirements&#34;&gt;Requirements&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A relatively slow trading system triggered by an hourly task scheduler during trading hours. I’m using Linux cron jobs for this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A non event-driven framework. I’m relying on ib_sync framework for my algorithms executed in interactive brokers. The alternative is an event-driven framework (e.g. official IB framework based on asyncio) based on my experience is hard to debug and would be an overkill for my low to medium frequency trading/ portfolio management system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automated trading execution and portfolio adjustments in relation to risks, signals and leverage cap.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data ingestion from multiple data sources/ APIs for signal processing, trade executions and logs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inclusion of safeguards and circuit breakers in place before firing any trades.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Notification through email for errors and daily updates @ start, middle and end of trading day.
-Able to integrate the above steps through Python.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;steps-taken&#34;&gt;Steps taken&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Without diving into the details of the code, here is the the general flow of my framework. The ‘main’ programs and execution flowcharts are appended at the end of the article.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Connect to my brokerage account as a new session.
Cancel any open orders. I adopt this option instead of ‘modifying orders’ as it’s much easier. If I were to modify orders, I would have to keep track of the number of filled orders and unfilled orders. As my algorithm is triggered hourly, any unfilled orders in that hourly slot are deemed to deviate significantly from the current price and the chance of being executed at the limit price is pretty low. That being said, in my next iteration, I would prefer to invest time in writing code to ‘modify orders’ instead of a simplistic ‘cancel orders’.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generate forecast i.e. Required leverage and weightage from different tickers. I currently write them as local files instead of committing them to a database or storing them as variables as they are more robust during live trading. I do not have to worry about concurrency issues (else codes have to consider mutex and locks), database downtime.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Obtain net liquidation value of account.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read in ticker weights and leverage from file written out in step 3.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create order files for different tickers including actions such as ‘Buy’, ‘Sell’ or ‘Do nothing’, Quantity and Limit price. At the moment, I’m using Adaptive Limit 7. Order from Interactive Brokers — which based on my understanding is a discretionary order with limit price as an upper bound. At the moment, I’m unwilling to invest more time on this to gain any further execution alpha as it could be a non-trivial task to dig into the bid-ask order books.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check if there are any errors from step 1 to 4 through an error flag. If there is any error, orders will not be sent. If everything cleared, the program will send the orders to the exchange.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trades, if any are recorded into a csv file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Save current snapshot which includes current positions, trades, net liquidation value and leverage utilized and margins.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If errors are encountered, an alert will be sent to my gmail.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Daily updates/ snapshots are sent to my gmail at the start, middle and end of session.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the program is triggered at 5am SGT (after US trading hours), the snapshots and trades information are committed to my database.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Disconnect from current session.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;technology-stack&#34;&gt;Technology stack&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are keen to know my technology stack, I’m currently using the following,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Linux Mint&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mint Box, 8GB RAM (but any laptop or virtual private server would suffice)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interactive brokers brokerage account (but the framework could be adapted to any brokerages with APIs)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interactive brokers gateway (IB Trade Worker Station is an alternative but I do not require any graphical user interface for my purpose)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ib_insync framework&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;word-of-caution&#34;&gt;Word of Caution&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This framework is not ideal for tick by tick or even bar by bar (seconds or minutes) trading algorithm since it’s not predicated on speed. An event-driven framework would be a better alternative if speed is required.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I’m relying on brokerage server side to keep track of the current positions, margins, leverage and orders. In the next stage of development beyond this Minimum Viable Product, I’m keen to develop my own accounting system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;appendix&#34;&gt;Appendix&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/post/img/prog1.png&#34; alt=&#34;/post/img/prog1.png&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/post/img/prog2.png&#34; alt=&#34;/post/img/prog2.png&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/post/img/flow1.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;/post/img/flow1.jpeg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Could volatility targeting increase risk-adjusted returns for quantitative strategies</title>
      <link>/post/volatility-targeting-could-potentially-increase-risk-adjusted-returns-for-any-quant-strategies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 11:50:49 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/volatility-targeting-could-potentially-increase-risk-adjusted-returns-for-any-quant-strategies/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;volatility-targeting-could-potentially-increase-risk-adjusted-returns-for-quantitative-strategies&#34;&gt;Volatility targeting could potentially increase risk-adjusted returns for quantitative strategies&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: Man AHL&amp;rsquo;s framework in this &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.man.com/maninstitute/volatility-is-back-better-to-target-returns-or-target-risk&#34;&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt; is used in the write-up here.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s say you researched and managed to find a quantitative strategy that suits your risk-reward preferences. How do you further improve your strategy while managing your risk?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A common way in the trend-following and risk parity space is to target risk - also known as volatility targeting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this article, I will present some simulations to bring you through my thought process on how I apply volatility targeting to my strategies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My simulations in this article showed that by applying volatility targeting, I could potentially increase my risk-adjusted returns by 10% (risk adjusted metric sharpe ratio increase from 1.62 to 1.79).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-volatility-targeting&#34;&gt;What is volatility targeting?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Volatility targeted funds are usually pegged to annualized volatility/ standard deviation. To provide some context, I will provide some intuition on how annualized standard deviation is derived.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Assuming variance of daily portfolio returns are independent (ignore serial correlation of returns), you could sum up variance of returns across days as follows,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Variance of portfolio returns across a year (252 trading days) = Var(ret1): Variance of return on day 1 + &amp;hellip;. + Var(ret252): Variance of return on day 252.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the variance of daily returns are the same, you could multiply variance of daily returns by 252 to obtain annualized variance of portfolio returns, Annual Variance = 252 * Var(ret)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To normalize it to annual standard deviation, you&amp;rsquo;ve to take a square root of Annual Variance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do you interpret this metric? Let&amp;rsquo;s say a strategy has an expected returns of 8% with annual standard deviation of 10%. Based on naive normality assumptions, there&amp;rsquo;s a 68% chance that the fund&amp;rsquo;s annualized return will be between -2% to 18%; and 95% chance that the fund&amp;rsquo;s returns will be between -12% to 28%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are couple of ways for fund managers to derive the volatilities,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One way is to simply find the standard deviation of returns over last X days and annualize it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A second way is to find the exponentially weighted standard deviation. See here (&lt;a href=&#34;https://financetrain.com/calculate-historical-volatility-using-ewma/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://financetrain.com/calculate-historical-volatility-using-ewma/&lt;/a&gt;) for further explanation. In my simulations below, I&amp;rsquo;m using this variation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;are-we-leaving-chips-on-the-table-can-we-afford-more-risk-when-should-we-take-chips-off-the-table&#34;&gt;Are we leaving chips on the table? Can we afford more risk? When should we take chips off the table?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below, I simulate a non volatility-targeted risk-parity portfolio rebalanced monthly i.e. portfolio is allocated across different asset classes based on risk rather than dollar value. Within asset classes, tickers are also risk-weighted. See here (&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Risk_parity&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Risk_parity&lt;/a&gt;) for further explanation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rolling standard deviation of raw portfolio is plotted below to illustrate the portfolio risk across time. From the diagram below, you would notice that there are periods where the portfolio risk is significantly below the 10% volatility target. Are there chips left on the table? Could you afford more risk?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are periods where portfolio risk is significantly above the 10% volatility target. Case in point during Covid sell-off? Should you be reducing risk instead?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/post/img/volatility curve.png&#34; alt=&#34;/post/img/volatility curve.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Equity curves and portfolio statistics are included below for benchmarking purposes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/post/img/raw_portfolio.png&#34; alt=&#34;/post/img/raw_portfolio.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Portfolio&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Annualized returns&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;Volatility&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;Sharpe&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;Max Drawdown&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;Return/Max Drawdown&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;Skewness&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Benchmark&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;8.97%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;5.5%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;1.62&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;-7.96%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;1.12&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;-1.14&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-if-we-target-risk-i-e-undertake-more-risk-during-calm-periods-and-less-risk-during-turbulent-periods&#34;&gt;What if we target risk? i.e. undertake more risk during calm periods and less risk during turbulent periods?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So does taking more risk during calm periods and reducing risk during turbulent periods pay off?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before, we proceed further, here are some assumptions I included in the simulations,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Portfolio is rebalanced monthly at the start of the trading day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On a daily basis, the algorithm checks for the current standard deviation of portfolio based on lookback period of 36 days. If it&amp;rsquo;s lesser than 10%, it will leverage proportionately (to a cap of 1.6 times). If it&amp;rsquo;s more than 10%, leverage will be reduced.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Leverage financing costs and commission fees are included.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on the equity curve and portfolio statistics below, the answer to the question posed earlier in the section is a resounding YES! It&amp;rsquo;s risk-reducing and returns enhancing to target volatility. Risk adjusted returns (Sharpe ratio) increased by 10% (1.62 to 1.79) and Return/ Max Drawdown is considerably higher. You would also notice that the negative skewness of the strategy improved considerably from -1.14 to -0.8.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/post/img/curve_lev.png&#34; alt=&#34;/post/img/curve_lev.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Portfolio&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Annualized returns&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;Volatility&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;Sharpe&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;Max Drawdown&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;Return/Max Drawdown&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;Skewness&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Benchmark&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;8.97%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;5.5%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;1.62&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;-7.96%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;1.12&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;-1.14&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Vol target (10%, max leverage of 1.6 times)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;13.92%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;7.4%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;1.79&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;-8.02%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;1.73&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;-0.8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;risk-reward-preferences&#34;&gt;Risk-reward preferences&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Above example is all but a single scenario. You could carry out a grid search to find the appropriate volatility target and leverage possibility space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve included the possibility space with respect to annualized returns, sharpe ratio, max drawdown to understand the risk-reward preferences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/post/img/Returns.png&#34; alt=&#34;/post/img/Returns.png&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/post/img/sharpe.png&#34; alt=&#34;/post/img/sharpe.png&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/post/img/drawdown.png&#34; alt=&#34;/post/img/drawdown.png&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/post/img/skewness.png&#34; alt=&#34;/post/img/skewness.png&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/post/img/kurtosis.png&#34; alt=&#34;/post/img/kurtosis.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;caveat&#34;&gt;Caveat&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: Above portfolio is currently in incubation prior to deployment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;full-tear-sheet-of-10-volatility-target-and-max-leverage-of-1-6-included-for-reference&#34;&gt;Full tear sheet of 10% volatility target and Max leverage of 1.6 included for reference&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/post/img/tear_sheet.png&#34; alt=&#34;/post/img/tear_sheet.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Framework for capital allocation</title>
      <link>/post/framework-for-capital-allocation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 11:50:49 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/framework-for-capital-allocation/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;framework-for-capital-allocation&#34;&gt;Framework for capital allocation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this resource starved world, capital is scarce. Every dollar that you own has its place and deserves to be allocated properly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, I already have a huge chunk of capital tied up in a diversified portfolio levered up to 1.4 times. Portfolio has (&amp;amp; expected to) outperformed/ matched up to market returns with 2 to 3 times lower risk - in terms of standard deviation and drawdown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But going forward, if I discover a strategy that exhibits appealing characteristics (e.g reasonably high returns with low or inverse correlation to broad markets, crisis alpha), how do I allocate capital to this strategy without increasing my leverage?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To answer this question, I developed a framework that I will adopt for each strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://app.lucidchart.com/documents/embeddedchart/75c86678-fec4-49cb-b4f8-568a9412e87e&#34; width=&#34;1200&#34; height=&#34;1200&#34; style=&#34;border: none;&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrating volatility targeting into Jarvis, my expert advisor</title>
      <link>/post/volatility-targeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 11:50:49 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/volatility-targeting/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;volatility-targeting&#34;&gt;Volatility targeting&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, I&amp;rsquo;ve a suite of toolkits integrated into my Jarvis that advises me on the investing decisions that I&amp;rsquo;ve to make on a daily basis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the latest feature I cobbled together on a Saturday evening, 2 weeks ago, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to measure the volatility of my portfolio formally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why I&amp;rsquo;m doing this is because managing risks in the form of volatility is easier than targeting returns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On any given day, it&amp;rsquo;s easier to predict volatility than returns itself because of its persistent nature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think of it as a coin flips with Binomal distribution: B ~ (n, p).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P is the probability for which you expect a positive expected payout.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And variance of this win-lose distribution is n * p * (1-p). This variance is easier to &amp;lsquo;predict&amp;rsquo; based on your win rates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But market is not simply a binomial distribution, it also needs to take into consideration the portfolio size exposed to market risks and sequence of returns (autocorrelation here) at any given day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Current distribution of my portfolio win rate is around 65 to 70%. But because of some negative skew in returns, my portfolio is languishing at status quo (0%) since start of the year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though my portfolio have outperformed the indexes by a factor of 2 to 3, the steep drawdown during March period of my portfolio could have been prevented if I&amp;rsquo;ve put a hedge early on (if I&amp;rsquo;ve done it through a systematic quant way) to maintain a fixed volatility target.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hence, I decided to integrate the volatility targeting feature into Jarvis that advises me daily on the amount of index hedge to place to maintain my portfolio at a constant volatility target; not a perfect way to maintain volatility target (since my portfolio is not perfectly correlated to index) but I find it cumbersome and potentially costly to sell off multiple counters on a daily basis. I used a global etf as a proxy to maintain my risk level since my portfolio has a global tilt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the volatility of my levered portfolio. Notice how it spiked up 5 times in the month of March this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/post/img/vol_target.png&#34; alt=&#34;/post/img/vol_target.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What volatility targeting does is to supposedly to turn the volatility curve into a straight line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may find the code below. I won&amp;rsquo;t delve into the details but this is essentially what it does,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Obtain my current positions from googlesheet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compute my portfolio value converted into SGD now and historically based on current positions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compute annual standard deviation (normal and exponential version shared by Robert Carver) of my portfolio based on past 36 days daily returns. Annual non exponential standard deviation returns of portfolio = Daily standard deviation of returns of portfolio * sqrt(252)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compute benchmark (VT) volatility&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compute &amp;lsquo;imperfect&amp;rsquo; hedge required to achieve volatility target of 15%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pushes a notification to me on how much additional/ lesser hedge is required&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;#Note: Volatility targeting

#Initialization
sapply(c(&amp;quot;ggplot2&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;plotly&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;quantmod&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;pushoverr&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;zoo&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;dplyr&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;roll&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PerformanceAnalytics&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;pushoverr&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;googlesheets&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;pracma&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;timeDate&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;riingo&amp;quot;), require, character.only = T)
source(&#39;util/extract_stock_prices.R&#39;)

rsd_file = Sys.getenv(&amp;quot;GOOGLESHEET&amp;quot;)
gs_auth(token = rsd_file)
suppressMessages(gs_auth(token = rsd_file, verbose = FALSE))

dat = gs_title(&amp;quot;Investment&amp;quot;)
gs_ws_ls(dat)   #tab names
data &amp;lt;- gs_read(ss=dat, ws = &amp;quot;debt_to_equity&amp;quot;, skip=0)
leverage = 1 + data$Ratio[3]
# leverage = 1
current_hedge_value = data$Ratio[nrow(data)]

currency = &amp;quot;SGD=X&amp;quot;
last_date = Sys.Date() - 200
benchmark = &amp;quot;VT&amp;quot;
num_counters = 24

##########################Obtain portfolio info##########################
# df_tickers = data.frame(tickers = c(&amp;quot;TLT&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;IEF&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;SPY&amp;quot;, ))
df_tickers &amp;lt;- gs_read(ss=dat, ws = &amp;quot;investment_live&amp;quot;, skip=0)
# df_tickers = subset(df_tickers, df_tickers$Ticker != &amp;quot;CNYB.AS&amp;quot;)
df_tickers = filter(df_tickers, num_units &amp;gt; 0)

current_value = sum(df_tickers$value)

df_tickers = df_tickers[, 1:5]
df_tickers[which(df_tickers$exch_rate_type == &amp;quot;SGDHKD=X&amp;quot;), 5] = &amp;quot;HKDSGD=X&amp;quot;

##########################Format data function##########################
#Create a time series of data, then merge in. Just filter out weekend only
data_format = function(ticker, num_units, currency, last_date){

  #Create date range
  create_date = function(i){
    return(last_date + i)
  }
  
  df = data.frame(Date = sapply(0:(Sys.Date() - last_date), create_date))
  df$Date = as.Date(df$Date, origin = &amp;quot;1970-01-1&amp;quot;)
  df$isWeekend = isWeekend(df$Date)
  df$Date = as.character(df$Date)
  
  #Read data
  data_temp = df_crawl_time_series(ticker, &amp;quot;1970-07-01&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;2030-12-30&amp;quot;)
  data_temp = subset(data_temp, data_temp$Date &amp;gt;= last_date &amp;amp; data_temp$Date &amp;lt;= Sys.Date())
  data = merge(df, data_temp, by = c(&amp;quot;Date&amp;quot;), all.x = T)

  #Fill NAs
  data = subset(data, data$isWeekend == F)
  
  if(is.na(data$Adj.Close[1])){
    data$Adj.Close[1] = data$Adj.Close[2]
  }

  if(is.na(data$Adj.Close[1])){
    data$Adj.Close[1] = data$Adj.Close[3]
  }
  
  if(is.na(data$Adj.Close[1])){
    data$Adj.Close[1] = data$Adj.Close[4]
  }
  
    
  data$Adj.Close = na.locf(data$Adj.Close)
  
  #Subset out data-frame
  df = data.frame(Date = data$Date, Price = data$Adj.Close, stringsAsFactors = F)
  
  #Read in num_units
  df$num_units = num_units
  
  #Subset date range
  df = subset(df, df$Date &amp;gt;= last_date &amp;amp; df$Date &amp;lt;= Sys.Date())
  
  #Read in currency
  currency = df_crawl_time_series(currency, &amp;quot;1970-07-01&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;2030-12-30&amp;quot;)
  currency$Adj.Close = na.locf(currency$Adj.Close)
  currency = subset(currency, select = c(&amp;quot;Date&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Adj.Close&amp;quot;))
  
  #Merge in currency
  df = df %&amp;gt;%
    left_join(., currency, by = c(&amp;quot;Date&amp;quot;))
  
  #Convert to local currency
  df$local_unit_value = df$Price * df$Adj.Close
  df$local_value = df$local_unit_value * df$num_units
  
  #Return date, portfolio value     
  df$Date = as.Date(df$Date)
  
  #ticker
  df$ticker = ticker
  
  df_sub = subset(df, df$Date &amp;gt;= last_date &amp;amp; df$Date &amp;lt;= Sys.Date())
    
  return(df_sub)    
}

########################Formatting portfolio function####################
portfolio_format = function(df_tickers, last_date){

i = 1
ticker_agg = data_format(df_tickers$Ticker[i], df_tickers$num_units[i], df_tickers$exch_rate_type[i], last_date)  

for(i in 2:nrow(df_tickers)){
  print(i)
  ticker_ind = data_format(df_tickers$Ticker[i], df_tickers$num_units[i], df_tickers$exch_rate_type[i], last_date)  
  ticker_agg = rbind(ticker_agg, ticker_ind)
}

portfolio = ticker_agg %&amp;gt;%
  group_by(Date) %&amp;gt;%
  summarize(portfolio_value = sum(local_value, na.rm = T),
            num_counters = n()
  )

portfolio$portfolio_value_adj = ifelse(portfolio$num_counters &amp;lt; num_counters, NA, portfolio$portfolio_value)

portfolio$upper_sd = mean(portfolio$portfolio_value_adj, na.rm = T) + 0.4 * sd(portfolio$portfolio_value_adj, na.rm = T)
portfolio$lower_sd = mean(portfolio$portfolio_value_adj, na.rm = T) - 0.4 * sd(portfolio$portfolio_value_adj, na.rm = T)
portfolio$portfolio_value_adj2 = ifelse((portfolio$portfolio_value_adj  &amp;gt; portfolio$upper_sd) | (portfolio$portfolio_value_adj  &amp;lt; portfolio$lower_sd),
                                        NA,
                                        portfolio$portfolio_value_adj)
portfolio$portfolio_value_adj2 = na.locf(portfolio$portfolio_value_adj2)

if(!is.na(current_value)){
  portfolio$portfolio_value_adj2[nrow(portfolio)] = current_value
}

portfolio$returns = ROC(portfolio$portfolio_value_adj2) * leverage
portfolio$returns_100 = portfolio$returns * 100

portfolio$roll_std = roll_sd(portfolio$returns, 36)
portfolio$roll_std_annual = portfolio$roll_std * (252 ^ 0.5)

df = portfolio

return(df)

}

##########################Find beta of portfolio######################################
#Find out how much of local_unit_value needed
find_beta = function(df, benchmark){
  
  price_bench = data_format(benchmark, num_units = 10, currency, last_date)
  price_bench$returns = ROC(price_bench$local_value)
  price_bench = subset(price_bench, select = c(&amp;quot;Date&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;returns&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;local_unit_value&amp;quot;))    
  names(price_bench)[2] = &amp;quot;returns_benchmark&amp;quot;

  df_agg = df %&amp;gt;%
    left_join(., price_bench, by = &amp;quot;Date&amp;quot;)
  
  reg = lm(df_agg$returns ~ df_agg$returns_benchmark)
  return(as.numeric(reg$coefficients[2]))
  
}

##########################Pure vol targeting######################################
#Find out how much of local_unit_value needed
#Account for leveraged %

find_vol_units = function(df, benchmark, leverage){
  
  price_bench = data_format(benchmark, num_units=10, currency, last_date)
  price_bench$returns = ROC(price_bench$local_value)
  price_bench = subset(price_bench, select = c(&amp;quot;Date&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;returns&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;local_unit_value&amp;quot;))    
  names(price_bench)[2] = &amp;quot;returns_benchmark&amp;quot;

  df_agg = df %&amp;gt;%
              left_join(., price_bench, by = &amp;quot;Date&amp;quot;)
  
  #Compute EMA of VT price. Loop number of units. And iteratively compute new portfolio value and EMA of SD. Find out closest number of VT units required.
  df_agg$square_returns_target = df_agg$returns_benchmark ^ 2
  df_agg$square_returns_target[1] = df_agg$square_returns_target[2]
  df_agg$ema_vol_target =  movavg(df_agg$square_returns_target, 36, type = &amp;quot;e&amp;quot;)
  df_agg$ema_sd_target = df_agg$ema_vol_target ^ 0.5 * (252 ^ 0.5)
  
  df_agg$square_returns = (df_agg$returns) ^ 2
  df_agg$square_returns[1] = df_agg$square_returns[2]
  df_agg$ema_vol =  movavg(df_agg$square_returns, 36, type = &amp;quot;e&amp;quot;)
  df_agg$ema_sd = df_agg$ema_vol ^ 0.5 * (252 ^ 0.5)
  
  
  return(df_agg)
}

##########################Generate df######################################
df = portfolio_format(df_tickers, last_date)
beta = find_beta(df, benchmark)
df = find_vol_units(df, benchmark, leverage)
reduce_times_exp = df$ema_sd[nrow(df) - 0]/ 0.15

##########################Find hedge required to target risk######################################
hedge = (df$portfolio_value_adj2[nrow(df)] - (df$portfolio_value_adj2[nrow(df)]/ reduce_times_exp)) * (df$ema_sd[nrow(df)] / df$ema_sd_target[nrow(df)])
hedge = round(hedge, 0)

##########################Pushing notifications to inform how much hedge is required######################################
msg = paste0(&amp;quot;You should hedge &amp;quot;, hedge, 
             &amp;quot; Current hedge value is &amp;quot;, current_hedge_value,
             &amp;quot; Additional hedge required &amp;quot;, (hedge - current_hedge_value),
             &amp;quot; Portfolio vol is &amp;quot;, round(df$ema_sd[nrow(df)], 3),
             &amp;quot; Benchmark vol is &amp;quot;, round(df$ema_sd_target[nrow(df)], 3)
)

print(msg)
plot(df$ema_sd)

if(abs(hedge - current_hedge_value) &amp;gt; 3000){
  pushover(message = msg, 
           user = Sys.getenv(&amp;quot;pushover_user&amp;quot;), app = Sys.getenv(&amp;quot;pushover_app&amp;quot;))
  
}

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
