<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jirong&#39;s sandbox on Jirong&#39;s sandbox</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Jirong&#39;s sandbox on Jirong&#39;s sandbox</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Designing, Building and Deploying a Fully Automated Algorithmic Trading System</title>
      <link>/post/designing-and-deploying-a-fully-automated-algorithmic-trading-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 11:50:49 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/designing-and-deploying-a-fully-automated-algorithmic-trading-system/</guid>
      <description>Designing, Building and Deploying a Fully Automated Algorithmic Trading System I wrote an article on Designing, Building and Deploying a Fully Automated Algorithmic Trading System. You may find the article in Medium link.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Could volatility targeting increase risk-adjusted returns for quantitative strategies</title>
      <link>/post/volatility-targeting-could-potentially-increase-risk-adjusted-returns-for-any-quant-strategies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 11:50:49 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/volatility-targeting-could-potentially-increase-risk-adjusted-returns-for-any-quant-strategies/</guid>
      <description>Volatility targeting could potentially increase risk-adjusted returns for quantitative strategies Note: Man AHL&amp;rsquo;s framework in this paper is used in the write-up here.
Let&amp;rsquo;s say you researched and managed to find a quantitative strategy that suits your risk-reward preferences. How do you further improve your strategy while managing your risk?
A common way in the trend-following and risk parity space is to target risk - also known as volatility targeting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Framework for capital allocation</title>
      <link>/post/framework-for-capital-allocation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 11:50:49 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/framework-for-capital-allocation/</guid>
      <description>Framework for capital allocation In this resource starved world, capital is scarce. Every dollar that you own has its place and deserves to be allocated properly.
Currently, I already have a huge chunk of capital tied up in a diversified portfolio levered up to 1.4 times. Portfolio has (&amp;amp; expected to) outperformed/ matched up to market returns with 2 to 3 times lower risk - in terms of standard deviation and drawdown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrating volatility targeting into Jarvis, my expert advisor</title>
      <link>/post/volatility-targeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 11:50:49 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/volatility-targeting/</guid>
      <description>Volatility targeting Currently, I&amp;rsquo;ve a suite of toolkits integrated into my Jarvis that advises me on the investing decisions that I&amp;rsquo;ve to make on a daily basis.
On the latest feature I cobbled together on a Saturday evening, 2 weeks ago, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to measure the volatility of my portfolio formally.
Why I&amp;rsquo;m doing this is because managing risks in the form of volatility is easier than targeting returns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapreduce using Java</title>
      <link>/post/mapreduce-in-java/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 11:50:49 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/mapreduce-in-java/</guid>
      <description>Mapreduce using java I haven&amp;rsquo;t coded in java in eons. The assignment (Mapreduce, Pig and Spark) I worked on over last 3 weeks is a good way to jolt me out from my comfort zone.
Java is something I need to brush up on before taking the Software Development Process module which requires me to write an android app. Argh!
Back to Mapreduce. It&amp;rsquo;s a useful framework if you&amp;rsquo;ve to summarise huge datasets (gigabytes, terabytes).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regime detection through hidden markov model</title>
      <link>/post/hidden_markov_model/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/hidden_markov_model/</guid>
      <description>Regime detection through hidden markov model It’s rumoured that in the early days of Renaissance Technologies - according to the book ‘The Man Who Solved the Market’ - hidden markov models are used for regime detection.
Here I am, a couple of decades later - employing this strategy. This will be integrated into my ‘Jarvis’ - a series of Algorithmic toolkits that advises me in all situations.
Hidden markov mode is a statistical unsupervised learning model used to model states.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regime detection through hidden markov model</title>
      <link>/project/hidden_markov_model/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/hidden_markov_model/</guid>
      <description>Regime detection through hidden markov model It’s rumoured that in the early days of Renaissance Technologies - according to the book ‘The Man Who Solved the Market’ - hidden markov models are used for regime detection.
Here I am, a couple of decades later - employing this strategy. This will be integrated into my ‘Jarvis’ - a series of Algorithmic toolkits that advises me in all situations.
Hidden markov mode is a statistical unsupervised learning model used to model states.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Embedding D3 interactive charts part 2</title>
      <link>/post/embedding-d3-interactive-charts-part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 11:50:49 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/embedding-d3-interactive-charts-part2/</guid>
      <description>Embedding D3 interactive charts Part 2 - Testing reading in of file from directory Just having fun - testing to see if I could embed D3 charts in my blog.
Seems like it works too! But I would have to upload the csv under public folder first.
   // set the dimensions and margins of the graph var margin = {top: 10, right: 30, bottom: 30, left: 60}, width = 460 - margin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Embedding D3 interactive charts</title>
      <link>/post/embedding-d3-interactive-charts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 11:46:40 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/embedding-d3-interactive-charts/</guid>
      <description>Embedding D3 interactive charts Just having fun - testing to see if I could embed D3 charts in my blog.
Seems like it works!
   // set the dimensions and margins of the graph var margin = {top: 10, right: 30, bottom: 30, left: 60}, width = 460 - margin.left - margin.right, height = 450 - margin.top - margin.bottom; // append the svg object to the body of the page var svg = d3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fuzzy matching with many to many matches without loops</title>
      <link>/post/fuzzy_matching_no_loops/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/fuzzy_matching_no_loops/</guid>
      <description>Fuzzy matching As a computer scientist graduate, I always strive to reduce my computational complexity through parallelization or vectorization!
Explicit loops in data science is the root of evil!
For loops &amp;amp; while loops have their places but definitely not in data science space (fairly broad statement here).
In this post here, I hope to show a really cool example that avoids the dreaded O(n square) complexity.
I will be using fuzzy matching to find the closet match of strings in data-frame 2, df2 against data-frame 1, df1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Latest lessons learnt from crawling</title>
      <link>/post/crawling-insights/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 11:46:49 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/crawling-insights/</guid>
      <description>Lessons learnt I just realised that there&amp;rsquo;s a quick way to understand the xpaths&amp;rsquo; patterns.
In the past, usually what I did is to manually eyeball to infer the patterns from the page source or inspect page.
Silly me!
1 quick way to understand the pattern is through the following,
 Right click on an element in a web page that you are interested in and click on &amp;lsquo;inspect&amp;rsquo; Right click on the node and click &amp;lsquo;copy&amp;rsquo; Copy full xpath  And paste to a notepad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free lunch does exist in Singapore - SRS analysis</title>
      <link>/post/srs_analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 11:46:49 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/srs_analysis/</guid>
      <description>SRS analysis I haven&amp;rsquo;t paid much attention to SRS contributions as a way to reduce taxable income. But lately, I realised you could boost investment portfolio returns through this avenue at literally 0 cost.
I find this blog post written by a local finance blogger to be really helpful in understanding the SRS contributions and withdrawal mechanics.
For my own understanding, I also did some quick analysis using google sheet (see &amp;lsquo;Analysis in google sheet&amp;rsquo; section) to evaluate if this works, and to my surprise, I found that free lunch does exist in Singapore!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back to Basics - Birth of an idea in the jungle</title>
      <link>/post/birth-of-an-idea-in-the-jungle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2019 11:46:49 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/birth-of-an-idea-in-the-jungle/</guid>
      <description>Birth of an idea of all places: In the Jungle Having to juggle both work and masters in computer science at the same time, it&amp;rsquo;s really hard to afford any more time to my side projects.
But back in August, I had a break away from both school and work by going back for reservist. As it&amp;rsquo;s really bored in there where I spent most of the time in a small building (with no aircon!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up a database for my Jarvis</title>
      <link>/post/jarvis_database/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2019 11:46:49 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/jarvis_database/</guid>
      <description>Setting up a database for my Jarvis As I run more sophiscated trading strategies, I require a proper database for training parameters and records.
Previously, I was using a mix of SQLite, RDA and CSV files - but going forward I will be using Mysql (workbench) to house my data.
Below is an example of database tables for my market neutral strategies. I will be using these tables for the following,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Market Neutral Strategy - DAX Index and EWG ETF</title>
      <link>/post/market_neutral_ewg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/market_neutral_ewg/</guid>
      <description>DAX index and Germany ETF I will keep it short in this post since I espoused on this strategy a couple of times.
I discovered another market neutral opportunity this month.
And this is based on ratio between Germany DAX index and MSCI based Germany ETF (EWG)
Based on backtest, sharpe ratio is close to 1.16.
The composition between these 2 indexes are largely similar and any significant deviation shouldn’t persist for long.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
