<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>betting on Jirong&#39;s sandbox</title>
    <link>/tags/betting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in betting on Jirong&#39;s sandbox</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 11:46:49 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/betting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Martingale Strategy - Double Down</title>
      <link>/post/martingale-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 11:46:49 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/martingale-strategy/</guid>
      <description>Martingale Strategy In this post, I will simulate a martingale strategy in Roulette&amp;rsquo;s context to highlight the potential risks associated with this strategy.
Double down! That&amp;rsquo;s essentially the essence of it.
Here&amp;rsquo;s a simple explanation of the strategy,
 The croupier spins the ball. If it&amp;rsquo;s red you win the amount you bet, black you lose the same amount If you win, you continue to bet the same amount (same as your 1st bet amount) If you lose, you double your bet amount And if your accumulated winnings hits a certain amount, you stop and leave the casino  So how would the strategy fare?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>World Cup - Singapore Pools odds</title>
      <link>/post/odds_analysis_worldcup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/odds_analysis_worldcup/</guid>
      <description>Hey it’s the world cup season - Tapping into a Machine Learning based paper Once again as a Singaporean citizen, there’re no other choices but to place my bets in Singapore pools. Betting in SG is not my preferred way to grow my wealth because of the crazy ~15% spread in Sg pools. In international sites, the spread is usually close to 3-5%. Oh well, that’s illegal.
But because this is the world cup season, I decide to make some small punts!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Betting in Singapore Pools</title>
      <link>/post/odds_analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/odds_analysis/</guid>
      <description>Finding value in Singapore Pools Of all places, this is the last place I expect to find value. But I found it - supposedly!
I compared the Singapore Pools Odds against Fivethirtyeight blog probabilities of teams’ winning various leagues.
The spread in Singpore Pools is often insane. In a typical 1X2 game, the odds is around 15% - as compared to a spread of 3% in overseas betting houses - which btw is illegal in Singapore.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>