<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>philosophy on Jirong&#39;s sandbox</title>
    <link>jironghuang.github.io/categories/philosophy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in philosophy on Jirong&#39;s sandbox</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2019 11:46:49 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="jironghuang.github.io/categories/philosophy/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Back to Basics - Birth of an idea in the jungle</title>
      <link>jironghuang.github.io/post/birth-of-an-idea-in-the-jungle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2019 11:46:49 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>jironghuang.github.io/post/birth-of-an-idea-in-the-jungle/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;birth-of-an-idea-of-all-places-in-the-jungle&#34;&gt;Birth of an idea of all places: In the Jungle&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having to juggle both work and masters in computer science at the same time, it&amp;rsquo;s really hard to afford any more time to my side projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But back in August, I had a break away from both school and work by going back for reservist. As it&amp;rsquo;s really bored in there where I spent most of the time in a small building (with no aircon!) in the middle of a jungle, I managed to revisit some of my past quant strategies, armed with my notebook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last Dec, I was exploring mean-reversion strategies with Kalman filter on spreads between 2 or more instruments. The math is elegant; backtest results are great but it&amp;rsquo;s really hard to operationalise it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The issue is - after you do all the feature transformation, it&amp;rsquo;s hard to visualize and compute basic statistics like,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expected profits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stop loss&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Checking feasibility based on real-market conditions such as bid-ask spreads&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes as a data trained individual, you wish to employ all the cool things in your arsenal. But one should focus on the key question,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does it really work?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In all honesty - across all disciplines - I think all of us should abide by the Occam&amp;rsquo;s Razor Philosphy: Translated from Latin, it means that Entities should not be multiplied beyond necessity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this current age where everyone tries to impress anyone with a brand new toy (techniques) such as deep learning, we&amp;rsquo;ve to always first think if the objective can be accomplished by simpler models. Do we really need complex models like Kalman Filter, Machine Learning, Deep Learning (LSTM for time series), Reinforcement Learning?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve back-tested all the above mentioned models. And at this point - at least in the quant &amp;amp; systematic trading space - I still think it&amp;rsquo;s pretty much a fancy toy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Really - what one should focus on for quant-based strategies is,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is it profitable with a reasonable amount of risks?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is it sustainable over a period of time across varying market conditions?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is it market neutral?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With your ability, could you operationalise it?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve since stripped away all the glamour and glitz associated with fancy techniques and went back to basics - using simple concepts such as moving average and standard deviations for my mean reversion techniques between Cointegrated instruments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without further ado, please find the conceptualisation of a &amp;lsquo;still profitable&amp;rsquo; idea that I deployed since 2 months ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Current tech stack that I use are: IB TWS, Quandl API, R, Mysql and Pushover API to notify me of the signals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;jironghuang.github.io/post/img/conceptualization.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;/post/img/conceptualization.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Investment Jarvis (In Ray Dalio&#39;s words, My Investment Principles)</title>
      <link>jironghuang.github.io/post/jarvis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 11:46:49 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>jironghuang.github.io/post/jarvis/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;jarvis&#34;&gt;Jarvis&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Humans are imperfect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Humans are prone to biases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Humans are dumb.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Humans have egos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Humans rely on intuitions which are way way overrated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And all these are blockers to sustainable positive performances in the area of investment portfolio management.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But not all is lost&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;ve found a way to aid me in my invesment decision making processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that&amp;rsquo;s Jarvis! My expert advisor to advise me what to do in different scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is how it works,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;during-normal-market-conditions&#34;&gt;During normal market conditions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;During normal market conditions, I will allocate Bonds and Cash % corresponding to my age. And this makes sense because as I grow older, my risk appetite should decrease.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I allocate 5% each to Singapore index, Gold/ Silver/ Commodities and Global Reits to hedge against different economic climate (see Ray Dalio&amp;rsquo;s explanation on all weather portfolio)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lastly, I will allocate (100 – 15 - age)/ 2 % to developed and emerging market indexes/ stocks respectively&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;during-crisis-2-sd-scenario&#34;&gt;During crisis (-2 SD scenario)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Buy low sell high. That&amp;rsquo;s my mantra. In the absence of rules, humans tend to do the opposite.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;During mayhem, when SnP 500 hits -2SD line in my project on what is low regression line for SnP 500 (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://jironghuang.github.io/project/what-is-low-regression-approach/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; for more info), that&amp;rsquo;s when I will be greedy. I will do a 50% leverage over my portfolio size and allocate 25% each to developed and emerging section of my portfolio.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SnP 500 is chosen as my barometer because it has the longest time series. And when US sneezes, everyone tends to catch a cold.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;during-crisis-3-sd-scenario&#34;&gt;During crisis (-3 SD scenario)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is the equivalent of an apocalypse. It has not even happened during the great recession&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m unsure if it will ever happen in my lifetime. But if it ever happens, I will be damn sure that I will leverage up till 100% of my portfolio.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;50% each will be allocated to developed and emerging section of my portfolio.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;selection-of-stuff-to-purchase&#34;&gt;Selection of stuff to purchase&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I only rebalance my portfolio once a month&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using 2 compasses (what is low &amp;amp; my 52% week high watchlist), I will sieve out tickers that are cheap and purchase them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When any of the portfolio pie gets too large, I will sell them to restore the balance in my portfolio&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Each counter with the exception of US, World and China will take up less than 5% of portfolio&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pls find my broad classification of developed and developing countries in diagram below&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;market-neutral-strategies&#34;&gt;Market neutral strategies&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a separate note, I also run market neutral strategies to try and profit in all economic climates. Returns from this section will tend to be lesser than my overall portfolio unless I leverage significantly. These are documented under &lt;a href=&#34;https://jironghuang.github.io/skin/skin-in-the-game/&#34;&gt;&amp;lsquo;Skin in the game&amp;rsquo;&lt;/a&gt; section of my blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;jironghuang.github.io/post/img/jarvis.png&#34; alt=&#34;/post/img/jarvis.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;snippets-of-my-jarvis&#34;&gt;Snippets of my Jarvis&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;if(data$Prop[which(data$Assets == &amp;quot;World + Developed (ex real estate)&amp;quot;)] &amp;gt; data$Prop[which(data$Assets == &amp;quot;Emerging&amp;quot;)]){
  
  msg = &amp;quot;Bro, you are overweight in Developed. Shift to Emerging\n&amp;quot;
  msg = paste(msg, &amp;quot;World is %&amp;quot;, 100 * data$Prop[which(data$Assets == &amp;quot;World + Developed (ex real estate)&amp;quot;)])
  msg = paste(msg, &amp;quot;Emerging is %&amp;quot;, 100 * data$Prop[which(data$Assets == &amp;quot;Emerging&amp;quot;)])
  
  pushover(message = msg, 
           user = Sys.getenv(&amp;quot;pushover_user&amp;quot;), app = Sys.getenv(&amp;quot;pushover_app&amp;quot;)
           )
}

if(data$Prop[which(data$Assets == &amp;quot;Emerging&amp;quot;)] &amp;gt; data$Prop[which(data$Assets == &amp;quot;World + Developed (ex real estate)&amp;quot;)]){
  
  msg = &amp;quot;Bro, you are overweight in Emerging. Shift to Developed\n&amp;quot;
  msg = paste(msg, &amp;quot;World is %&amp;quot;, 100 * data$Prop[which(data$Assets == &amp;quot;World + Developed (ex real estate)&amp;quot;)])
  msg = paste(msg, &amp;quot;Emerging is %&amp;quot;, 100 * data$Prop[which(data$Assets == &amp;quot;Emerging&amp;quot;)])
  
  pushover(message = msg, 
           user = Sys.getenv(&amp;quot;pushover_user&amp;quot;), app = Sys.getenv(&amp;quot;pushover_app&amp;quot;)
  )
}

if(100 * (data$Prop[which(data$Assets == &amp;quot;Bonds&amp;quot;)] + data$Prop[which(data$Assets == &amp;quot;Cash&amp;quot;)]) &amp;gt; data$Prop[which(data$Assets == &amp;quot;Age&amp;quot;)]){
  
  msg = &amp;quot;Bro, you are overweight in Bonds and Cash relative to your age. Shift it out!!!\n&amp;quot;
  msg = paste(msg, &amp;quot;Bonds is %&amp;quot;, 100 * data$Prop[which(data$Assets == &amp;quot;Bonds&amp;quot;)])
  msg = paste(msg, &amp;quot;Cash is %&amp;quot;, 100 * data$Prop[which(data$Assets == &amp;quot;Cash&amp;quot;)])
  
  pushover(message = msg, 
           user = Sys.getenv(&amp;quot;pushover_user&amp;quot;), app = Sys.getenv(&amp;quot;pushover_app&amp;quot;)
  )
}

if(100 * (data$Prop[which(data$Assets == &amp;quot;Bonds&amp;quot;)] + data$Prop[which(data$Assets == &amp;quot;Cash&amp;quot;)]) &amp;lt; data$Prop[which(data$Assets == &amp;quot;Age&amp;quot;)]){
  
  msg = &amp;quot;Bro, you are underweight in Bonds and Cash relative to your age. Shift it out!!!\n&amp;quot;
  msg = paste(msg, &amp;quot;Bonds is %&amp;quot;, 100 * data$Prop[which(data$Assets == &amp;quot;Bonds&amp;quot;)])
  msg = paste(msg, &amp;quot;Cash is %&amp;quot;, 100 * data$Prop[which(data$Assets == &amp;quot;Cash&amp;quot;)])
  
  pushover(message = msg, 
           user = Sys.getenv(&amp;quot;pushover_user&amp;quot;), app = Sys.getenv(&amp;quot;pushover_app&amp;quot;)
  )
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
