<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>engineering on Jirong&#39;s sandbox</title>
    <link>/jironghuang.github.io/tags/engineering/</link>
    <description>Recent content in engineering on Jirong&#39;s sandbox</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 11:50:49 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/jironghuang.github.io/tags/engineering/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Developing a performance monitoring component in my fully automated algorithmic trading system</title>
      <link>/jironghuang.github.io/post/designing-and-deploying-a-fully-automated-algorithmic-trading-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 11:50:49 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/jironghuang.github.io/post/designing-and-deploying-a-fully-automated-algorithmic-trading-system/</guid>
      <description>Developing a performance monitoring system for my algorithmic trading system It&amp;rsquo;s one thing to backtest your signals and forecasts on historical data but it&amp;rsquo;s a completely different animal in terms of execution. I have written about this here.
Another important component of setting up an algorithmic trading system is performance monitoring. Some important questions I had in mind while developing this component,
 How do I measure my slippage? Commissions paid?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Designing, Building and Deploying a Fully Automated Algorithmic Trading System</title>
      <link>/jironghuang.github.io/post/developing-an-accounting-and-performance-monitoring-system-for-my-algorithmic-trading-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 11:50:49 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/jironghuang.github.io/post/developing-an-accounting-and-performance-monitoring-system-for-my-algorithmic-trading-system/</guid>
      <description>Designing, Building and Deploying a Fully Automated Algorithmic Trading System As I developed several inter-day trading/ portfolio management algorithms, I also embarked on a journey in parallel to develop a fully automated execution framework that could satisfy my requirements.
Previously orders were executed manually after signals are generated automatically.
Requirements  A relatively slow trading system triggered by an hourly task scheduler during trading hours. I’m using Linux cron jobs for this.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>