<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>algo on Jirong&#39;s sandbox</title>
    <link>/tags/algo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in algo on Jirong&#39;s sandbox</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/algo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Market Neutral Strategy - DAX Index and EWG ETF</title>
      <link>/post/market_neutral_ewg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/market_neutral_ewg/</guid>
      <description>DAX index and Germany ETF I will keep it short in this post since I espoused on this strategy a couple of times.
I discovered another market neutral opportunity this month.
And this is based on ratio between Germany DAX index and MSCI based Germany ETF (EWG)
Based on backtest, sharpe ratio is close to 1.16.
The composition between these 2 indexes are largely similar and any significant deviation shouldn’t persist for long.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Market Neutral Strategy - FTSE Index and EWU ETF</title>
      <link>/post/market_neutral_ewu/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/market_neutral_ewu/</guid>
      <description>UK index and UK ETF I discovered another market neutral opportunity this month.
And this is based on ratio between FTSE 100 index and MSCI based UK ETF (EWU)
Based on backtest, sharpe ratio is close to 0.9.
The composition between these 2 indexes are largely similar and any significant deviation shouldn’t persist for long.
The optimal lookback period for the MA component in bollinger band is approximately 40 days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Market Neutral Strategy - SnP500 (SPY) to Berkshire Hathaway Ratio</title>
      <link>/post/market_neutral/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/market_neutral/</guid>
      <description>Market neutral strategy As the negative news pile up (trade wars, slump in economy growths, etc), I sought for market neutral stategies that could perform well in any market environment.
An idea that struck me recently is to exploit the pair between Berkshire and SnP 500 ETF.
The SnP500 ETF/ Berkshire ratio has been falling over the years - insinuating that Berkshire still outperforms the index in the last couple of years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Translating Ernest Chan Kalman Filter Strategy Matlab and Python Code Into R</title>
      <link>/post/translating-ernest-chan-kalman-filter-strategy-matlab-and-python-code-into-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:15:53 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/translating-ernest-chan-kalman-filter-strategy-matlab-and-python-code-into-r/</guid>
      <description>Translating Ernest Chan Kalman Filter Strategy Matlab and Python Code Into R I&amp;rsquo;m really intrigued by Ernest Chan&amp;rsquo;s approach in Quant Trading.
Often in the retail trading space, what &amp;lsquo;gurus&amp;rsquo; preach often sounds really dubious. But Ernest Chan is different. He&amp;rsquo;s sincere, down-to-earth and earnest (meant to be a pun here).
In my first month of deploying algo trading strategies, I focus mainly on mean-reversion strategies - paricularly amongst pairs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Find Country Pairs for Mean Reversion Strategy</title>
      <link>/post/how-i-find-country-pairs-for-mean-reversion-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Dec 2018 12:30:03 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/how-i-find-country-pairs-for-mean-reversion-strategy/</guid>
      <description>How I Find Country Pairs for Mean Reversion Strategy As mentioned in my previous post here, the first step for a mean reversion strategy is to conduct some background quantitative research.
Step 1 First, I use a pair trading function to loop across 800+ country pairs (created from combination function),
pair_trading = function(stock1, stock2, trade_amount, finance_rates, start_date, end_date, prop_train, enter_z_score, exit_z_score){ ## More codes here ## Return this key_info = list( ticker = c(stock1, stock2), start_date = start_date, trade_table = data_trade, sharpe = c(sharpeRatioTrainset, sharpeRatioTestset), half_life = half_life, profits = data_trade_stats, max_drawdown = c(table.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research to Production Pipeline for Mean Reversion</title>
      <link>/post/research-to-production-pipeline-for-mean-reversion/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Dec 2018 18:07:19 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/research-to-production-pipeline-for-mean-reversion/</guid>
      <description>Research to Production Pipeline for Mean Reversion Here is a high level overview of something that I&amp;rsquo;m working on.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been grappling with the finite state automata Event Driven Computing transitions and I kinda sorted it out for production use.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>