<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>simulation on Jirong&#39;s sandbox</title>
    <link>/jironghuang.github.io/categories/simulation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in simulation on Jirong&#39;s sandbox</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 11:46:49 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/jironghuang.github.io/categories/simulation/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Martingale Strategy - Double Down</title>
      <link>/jironghuang.github.io/post/martingale-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 11:46:49 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/jironghuang.github.io/post/martingale-strategy/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;martingale-strategy&#34;&gt;Martingale Strategy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this post, I will simulate a martingale strategy in Roulette&amp;rsquo;s context to highlight the potential risks associated with this strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Double down! That&amp;rsquo;s essentially the essence of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a simple explanation of the strategy,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The croupier spins the ball. If it&amp;rsquo;s red you win the amount you bet, black you lose the same amount&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you win, you continue to bet the same amount (same as your 1st bet amount)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you lose, you double your bet amount&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And if your accumulated winnings hits a certain amount, you stop and leave the casino&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how would the strategy fare? To explain, I will use Monte Carlo with a Bernoulli distribution for each roulette spin (X ~ B(1, 0.48)).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;simulate-strategy-10-runs-times&#34;&gt;Simulate strategy 10 runs/ times&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here, I simulate the strategy of 10 times. Think of it in this way, there&amp;rsquo;re 10 alternate universes which you exist and you play the same game 10 times. Or you can just simply treat this as going back to the casino on 10 separate days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the chart below, you will notice that for some runs; because of a sequence of bad luck, the losses quick spiralled!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/jironghuang.github.io/post/img/10_simulations.png&#34; alt=&#34;/post/img/10_simulations.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;simulate-strategy-1000-runs-times-and-compute-the-mean&#34;&gt;Simulate strategy 1000 runs/ times and compute the mean&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, for a more robust interpretation, I went on to simulate this strategy 1000 times and computed the mean and standard deviation. You will notice that the strategy eventually converges to a desired terminal value. In this case, it&amp;rsquo;s $80. So essentially, out of 1000 simulations, all of them reaches my profit target!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However the the risk is enormous. Near the average 120th run, the standard deviation sky-rocketed to 120,000. I&amp;rsquo;m unsure if anyone could stomach this loss at any one point of time. The journey matters!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/jironghuang.github.io/post/img/1000_simulations.png&#34; alt=&#34;/post/img/1000_simulations.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/jironghuang.github.io/post/img/simulation_sd.png&#34; alt=&#34;/post/img/simulation_sd.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;insights-from-this-strategy&#34;&gt;Insights from this strategy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Martingale strategy - to put it simply - is a win small, lose potentially huge strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this strategy, you will win 100% of the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the question is, do you have the money (or infinite bankroll) to tide through tough times?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
