<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>firstPrinciples on Jirong&#39;s sandbox</title>
    <link>/tags/firstprinciples/</link>
    <description>Recent content in firstPrinciples on Jirong&#39;s sandbox</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/firstprinciples/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Using exponential distribution to estimate frequency of occurence</title>
      <link>/post/exp_distrib/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/exp_distrib/</guid>
      <description>Simulating product failures I’m inspired by this post here (http://www.programmingr.com/examples/neat-tricks/sample-r-function/rexp/). And decided to expand on the example.
Say you are an owner of a computer store and you would like to estimate the frequency of warranty repairs - and the ensuing costs.
Here’s the scenario with the accompanying assumptions
 Each computer is expected to last an average of 7 years You only sell 1000 computers at the start of each year You sell computer from 2019 to 2025  First, I simulate an exponential distribution of 1000 points for 7 years; and place a time index of 2019 to 2025</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sampling With Replacement Through First Principles</title>
      <link>/post/sampling-with-replacement-through-first-principles/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/sampling-with-replacement-through-first-principles/</guid>
      <description>Sampling with replacement Hello! It&amp;rsquo;s me once again attempting to explain things from first principles - a term popularized by Elon Musk.
I will use some psudeo code - on sampling with replacement for weights - to aid my explanation.
Earlier in the week, I attempted to write a simple function from scratch but I gave up after realising that it will take me more than 15 mins! Difficulties lies in the multiple switch statements in defining the intervals.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>